

**E-mail**: snehamittal.1403@gmail.com **Website**: https://snehamittal.github.io/ **Github**: https://github.com/snehaMittal

> 7744/64 3rd floor Fasih Building Roshanara Road near Clock Tower Delhi - 110007 Phone: +91 96545719711

### **PROFILE**

I am a fourth year B.tech student, proficient in developing android applications. Extensive experience in object-oriented programming, developing and testing. Quickly learn and master new technologies; have successfully worked in both team and self-directed settings. Excellent understanding of programming language, having good communication and project management skills is what makes me stand out and proves me a right candidate. I am passionate to learn and get experience in every way possible.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### ANDROID DEVELOPMENT

Moscow Pvt Ltd (June,2018 - August, 2018)

## **INTERN**

- Developed an android app for the company from the scratch.
- Firebase Database is used.

#### SOFTWARE TESTING INTERN

#### DPD Technologies LLP (Nov., 2017 - Feb., 2018)

- Tested their software "queuebuster" (android and web version)
- Developed an automatic testing tool form core for their software (android version) using appium and selenium in java language.

# **EDUCATION**

B.TECH (CSE) Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi

**2015 - Present** 

Result: 82.60% (Upto 6th Sem)

CLASS XII St.Thomas' School , Delhi

2014 - 2015 Result : 93.20%

CLASS X St.Thomas' School , Delhi

2012 - 2013 Result : 91.20%

### SKILLS

• Language: Java | C++

• **Databases** : MySQL | Firebase | SqlLite

• Platforms: Android Studio | IntelliJ | Eclipse

## **PROJECTS**

• ENTERTAINMENT ADDA: This application is a collection of Movies and TV shows. It displays the information like genre, cast, synopsis, trailer, etc of the selected movie or show. The application lets you add the movies and TV shows to your favourites and also allows you to share it over social media with your friends. Rest API, Glide and Retrofit is used in it.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/detailsid=com.geeky2developers.pulkit.onestop

• **ONESTOP**: This application provides android users with commonly used applications such as Calculator, Flashlight, Stopwatch, Compass and To Do List in just one application. In order to enhance the experience of the user, the application also contains shortcuts to: Facebook, Google, WhatsApp and Gmail. The key features of the application are, that it saves memory, saves time for searching apps in the phone and there is no need to download utility apps separately.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/detailsid=com.geekydevelopers.entertainmentAdda

- TEXT RECOGNITION CAMERA: :An android based application for Text recognition from Camera by OCR technology and Mobile Vision API.
- **MINESWEEPER**: An android game with the goal to uncover all the squares that do not contain mines. It's features are: variable minefield, classical gameplay, adapted to screen.
- OTHELLO: A two player board game developed for android. Basically, there are two sided discs on a board black and white. The goal is to end the game with as many discs showing your color as possible. To do this, you must sandwich your opponents discs between a piece (showing your own color) currently on the board, and the piece you're putting down.
- VisionAid: Currently working on project as a part of my minor project which will be an android launcher for blind people for using smartphones and tablets. It will have a voice-guide that tells the user everything that it's happening in the device (screen off/on, rotation, incoming call, etc.). The app will allow the user to: Listen to music, use a voice recorder, send and receive SMS, receive and make calls, create and delete alarms, create and delete contacts, browse the web with Google engine.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Secured 91.1% national percentile in Quantitative Ability and 98.3% national percentile in Computer Programming.
- 100+ downloads on OneStop app published on PlayStore .
- 100+ downloads on Entertainment Adda app published on PlayStore